{
    "questions" : [
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [1~2] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "29_1_img",
            "option_1"      : "① ",
            "option_2"      : "② ",
            "option_3"      : "③ ",
            "option_4"      : "④ ",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : The view is nice here. Shall we get off for a while and take a picture?\nMan : Yes. We still have a lot of time, so let's park a car near here and look around.",
            "correctAnswer" : "② ",
            "score"         : "3",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [1~2] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "29_2_img",
            "option_1"      : "① ",
            "option_2"      : "② ",
            "option_3"      : "③ ",
            "option_4"      : "④ ",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Where did the key go? I have to get off work, but I can't see the car keys.\nMan : Is that so? Well (after a while), oh, here it is.\nWoman : Oh, it was down there.",
            "correctAnswer" : "① ",
            "score"         : "3",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "3. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  전화기를 끄는 게 좋겠어.",
            "option_2"      : "②  전화기를 집에 두고 왔어.",
            "option_3"      : "③  전화로 말하면 될 것 같아.",
            "option_4"      : "④  전화번호를 몰라서 못 했어.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : You've waited a long time, right? There's some traffic.\nMan : It's okay. But why didn't you answer the phone?\nWoman : I left my phone at home.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  전화기를 집에 두고 왔어.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "4. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  그러면 먹을 것 좀 사 올게요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  그러니까 오늘은 일찍 문 닫아요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  그런데 문을 닫아서 그냥 왔어요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  그래서 아까 라면하고 물을 샀어요.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : I'm a little hungry because I work late. Is the canteen on the first floor still open?\nWoman : It's usually open until 10 o'clock, right?\nMan : Then I'll buy you something to eat.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  그러면 먹을 것 좀 사 올게요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "5. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  처음 봤을 때보다 낫네.",
            "option_2"      : "②  직접 보니까 좀 재미있던데.",
            "option_3"      : "③  정말? 그럴 줄 알았으면 나도 볼걸.",
            "option_4"      : "④  그래? 재미있을 것 같아서 보려고 했는데.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : How about this movie? Would it be fun.\nWoman : I saw it last week and it was worse than I expected.\nMan : Is that so? I was going to watch it because I thought it would be fun.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  그래? 재미있을 것 같아서 보려고 했는데.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "6. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  네. 스트레스가 풀리는 것 같아요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  네. 한번 올라가 보고 싶어지네요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  네. 지금 바로 내려갔으면 좋겠어요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  네. 이렇게 한 번씩 오면 좋더라고요.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I didn't know our company building was this high.\nMan : Don't you feel really good to come up to the top like this?\nWoman: yes I think I'm getting rid of stress.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  네. 스트레스가 풀리는 것 같아요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "7. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  승차 시 주의 사항",
            "option_2"      : "②  교통사고가 일어난 이유",
            "option_3"      : "③  빗길 운전의 위험성",
            "option_4"      : "④  안전벨트 매는 것의 중요성",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Look at this article. I must fasten my seat belt from now on.\nMan : What's the content? Well, (like reading a newspaper, the feeling of reading an unusual article) The express bus slipped in the rain.\nWoman : yeah But few people got hurt because they were wearing seatbelts.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  안전벨트 매는 것의 중요성",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "8. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  탄 냄비를 쉽게 닦는 방법",
            "option_2"      : "②  냄비를 사용할 때 주의할 점",
            "option_3"      : "③  설거지 시간을 줄이는 방법",
            "option_4"      : "④  끓는 물로 설거지할 때 주의할 점",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : It's hard to wash the dishes when the pot burns. No matter how many times you wipe it, it won't be clean. In that case, lemons help. First, put the lemon into thin slices in a burnt pot, then pour water and bring to a boil. If you boil it for 5 to 10 minutes and wipe it, it will be clean.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  탄 냄비를 쉽게 닦는 방법",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "9. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  실내조명을 바꾸는 순서",
            "option_2"      : "②  조명에 따라 달라지는 분위기",
            "option_3"      : "③  부엌에 어울리는 조명 색깔",
            "option_4"      : "④  같은 색 조명을 사용하는 까닭",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : If you want to change the indoor atmosphere, try changing the lights. It's because the indoor atmosphere can be different depending on the lighting. If you put yellow lights in the kitchen, you can eat in a warm atmosphere. Even if it's the same color, if you change the brightness, you can create a different atmosphere.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  부엌에 어울리는 조명 색깔",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "10. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  사고가 일어난 원인",
            "option_2"      : "②  사고 처리가 늦어진 이유",
            "option_3"      : "③  사고로 인한 피해 상황",
            "option_4"      : "④  사고 피해에 대한 보상 방법",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Yesterday afternoon, a 42-year-old Mr. Kim slipped while fishing on the coast of Inju City. Recently, this kind of accident has already occurred for the fourth time in this area. It's because the rocks were slippery due to the continuous rain for several days, and the wind blew strongly at the time of the accident. Those who are fishing in this area should be careful.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  사고가 일어난 원인",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "11. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  이 테니스장은 샤워장이 없다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  여자는 테니스장을 이용하려고 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  남자는 예약 시간을 바꾸고 싶어한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  이 테니스장은 주말에 문을 열지 않는다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : hey I'd like to use the tennis court in the park. Can you use it this Saturday at 5 p.m.?\nMan : Wait a minute. The reservation is already over at 5 o'clock. You can make a reservation after 7 p.m.\nWoman : Then please make a reservation for that time. You can also use the shower, right?\nMan : I'm sorry, but I can't use it because I'm fixing the shower these days.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  여자는 테니스장을 이용하려고 한다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "12. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  에너지가 없어도 체온을 올릴 수 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  땀을 흘리면 많은 에너지를 사용하게 된다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  체온이 내려가면 몸의 근육을 움직여서 열을 낸다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  날씨가 더울수록 몸은 더 많은 에너지를 사용한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : When does our body use more energy, summer or winter? There are many people who think it's a summer that usually sweats a lot. However, it uses more energy in the cold winter. When the body temperature drops due to the cold, our body moves muscles to raise the body temperature to make heat. Because energy is used in this process.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  체온이 내려가면 몸의 근육을 움직여서 열을 낸다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "13. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  수업료는 따로 받지 않는다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  이 특강은 수요일마다 열린다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  기타는 자기가 가지고 와야 된다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  전화나 인터넷으로 신청할 수 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I would like to inform you for a moment. Our cultural center will hold a special lecture on guitar next Wednesday with famous guitar player Park Si-eun. Applications can be made online, and applications are not accepted over the phone. The tuition fee, including the class materials, is 10,000 won, and you have to prepare the others yourself. We hope that many people who are interested in other things will participate.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  기타는 자기가 가지고 와야 된다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "14. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  한두 잔의 커피는 건강에 좋다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  커피를 많이 마시는 것은 안 좋다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  잠이 올 때는 커피를 마셔야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  일할 때는 커피를 마시지 말아야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Why are you so sleepy? I have to finish this by today. I should have a cup of coffee.\nWoman : Are you going to drink again? One or two drinks a day would be fine, but it's not good for your health if you drink too much. Just go outside and come back.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  커피를 많이 마시는 것은 안 좋다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "15. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  아이에게 휴대 전화를 사 주는 게 낫다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  나이가 어릴수록 휴대 전화가 필요하다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  아이는 부모가 어디에 있는지 아는 게 좋다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  급한 일이 생기면 아이에게 빨리 연락해야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Does your child have a cell phone? My child said he has all his classmates, so he asked me to buy it, but I'm still young, so I'm wondering if I should buy it for him.\nWoman : I bought it for my kid when he was 10 years old. I have a cell phone, so it's nice to be able to contact each other when there's something urgent. And it's also reassuring to know where the child is.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  아이에게 휴대 전화를 사 주는 게 낫다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "16. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  회의 시간 전에 생각을 정리해 와야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  다양한 의견을 모은 후에 회의를 해야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  회의 때 덜 중요한 이야기는 넘어가야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  의견을 말할 수 있게 회의 시간이 더 길어져야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : I think it's good for the new blind of our team to have a short meeting. It was good to talk about important things.\nWoman : It's good to have a short meeting, but I don't think I have enough time to give an opinion. I wish I had enough time to talk about this and that. If you don't say it from time to time, it's easy to move on.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  의견을 말할 수 있게 회의 시간이 더 길어져야 한다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "17. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  회사에는 능력 있는 신입 사원이 많아야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  회사는 신입 사원에게 다양한 교육을 해야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  회사에서 경력 사원을 뽑으려고 하는 것은 당연하다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  회사는 경력이 없는 사람에게 더 많은 기회를 줘야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Our company is hiring another experienced employee. There aren't many advertisements for recruiting new employees these days. So how can people with no work experience get a job at a company?\nWoman : The company prefers experienced employees. Because new employees take time to adjust to work. If you hire experienced employees, you can save time and money for education and training.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  회사에서 경력 사원을 뽑으려고 하는 것은 당연하다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "18. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  다른 바지를 입어 본다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  바지를 받을 주소를 쓴다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  바지의 사이즈를 확인한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  마음에 드는 바지를 찾아본다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : I like this job. Is there anything bigger than this?\nWoman : I'm sorry, but all the sizes you're looking for are out and we don't have them in our store. If you write the address on the order form, I'll send it to you by courier. Or would you like to see something else?\nMan : no I like it the most among the things I've tried on, so I'll order it.\nWoman: Would you? Wait a minute I'll bring you the order form.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  바지를 받을 주소를 쓴다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "19. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  서둘러 퇴근한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  1층 안내실에 간다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  컴퓨터실 창문을 닫는다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  여자에게서 우산을 빌린다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Uh, it's raining. Is the window of the computer room closed?\nWoman : Yes, I'm on my way back from closing.\nMan : But why is it raining so much all of a sudden? I didn't bring an umbrella. Please go to the information room on the 1st floor. If you go there, you can borrow an umbrella for free. But it's almost time to get off work, so I'll have to go quickly. A lot of people borrowed it.\nMan : Is that so? Thanks.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  1층 안내실에 간다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "20. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  여자에게 축제 준비 자료를 만들어 준다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  축제 시작 시간에 대한 이메일을 보낸다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  전화번호를 찾아 자원 봉사자에게 연락한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  자원 봉사자들이 이메일을 확인했는지 알아본다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Mr. Lee, you sent all the emails to the volunteers who were supposed to come to the festival, right?\n Woman : yes But there are two people who haven't checked the email yet.\nMan : Is that so? The start time of the festival has changed, so they should check it out. Do you want me to call?\nWoman : Oh, will you do that? Thank you . If you look at the preparation materials I gave you yesterday, there will be the phone numbers of the volunteers.\nMan : Yes, here it is. Please tell me the name of the person who didn't check the email.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  전화번호를 찾아 자원 봉사자에게 연락한다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "21. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  이곳은 사람들에게 별로 알려져 있지 않다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  이곳에는 앉아 있을 곳이 없어서 불편하다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이곳은 책이 많아서 작가들이 자주 찾는다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  이곳에는 이야기를 나눌 수 있는 공간이 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Today, I came here because there is a place that is popular with many people these days. Why do so many people visit this place?\nMan : I think you like it because there is a space where you can relax while looking at the book. If you need a book, you can sit down and read it. We can talk about books while drinking coffee. And at our bookstore, we have a meeting with the author once a month, and the customers really like it. I think the reason why our store is loved is that there are so many books that are hard to find in other places.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  이곳에는 이야기를 나눌 수 있는 공간이 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "22. 남자는 누구인지 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  작가",
            "option_2"      : "②  서점 주인",
            "option_3"      : "③  도서관 직원",
            "option_4"      : "④  커피숍 손님",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Today, I came here because there is a place that is popular with many people these days. Why do so many people visit this place?\nMan : I think you like it because there is a space where you can relax while looking at the book. If you need a book, you can sit down and read it. We can talk about books while drinking coffee. And at our bookstore, we have a meeting with the author once a month, and the customers really like it. I think the reason why our store is loved is that there are so many books that are hard to find in other places.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  서점 주인",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "23. 남자는 무엇을 하고 있는지 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  새로운 사업의 비용을 요청하고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  새로운 사업의 내용을 평가하고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  새로운 사업의 대상을 분석하고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  새로운 사업의 필요성을 설명하고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : As you all know, there are more and more foreign students these days. Like other universities, our school is trying to attract foreign students. In fact, we can't accept international students because we don't have enough dormitories. So I think we should prepare a dedicated dormitory for foreign students. The dedicated dormitory should have at least 120 rooms, and a computer room, a reading room, a dining room, as well as a support center for foreigners and cultural exchange facilities are required. From now on, we need to build a new dormitory so that more international students can visit our school.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  새로운 사업의 필요성을 설명하고 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "24. 이 사업을 실시하는 이유가 무엇인지 고르십시오. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  문화 교류를 더 활발하게 하기 위해",
            "option_2"      : "②  외국인 지원 시설을 다양화하기 위해",
            "option_3"      : "③  외국인 유학생을 많이 유치하기 위해",
            "option_4"      : "④  편의 시설들을 한곳에 모아 놓기 위해",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : As you all know, there are more and more foreign students these days. Like other universities, our school is trying to attract foreign students. In fact, we can't accept international students because we don't have enough dormitories. So I think we should prepare a dedicated dormitory for foreign students. The dedicated dormitory should have at least 120 rooms, and a computer room, a reading room, a dining room, as well as a support center for foreigners and cultural exchange facilities are required. From now on, we need to build a new dormitory so that more international students can visit our school.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  외국인 유학생을 많이 유치하기 위해",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "25. 여자의 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (4점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  텔레비전 광고는 믿을 수 없는 것이 많다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  탄산음료는 어른들보다 아이들에게 더 해롭다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  텔레비전 방송에 나오는 광고의 수를 줄여야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  탄산음료는 어린이 프로그램 시간을 피해 광고해야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I'd like to talk about children's advertising. Did you know that you can't advertise sodas like coke or cider before 9 p.m. in Sweden? Advertising is also prohibited because soda is bad for children's health. According to experts, children are more affected by television commercials than adults. That's why we shouldn't broadcast advertisements that can harm children's health. There are many children who like soda in our country. I think we should ban these advertisements, at least when we mainly do children's programs.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  탄산음료는 어린이 프로그램 시간을 피해 광고해야 한다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "26. 여자가 제시한 주장의 근거로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (3점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  관찰 결과",
            "option_2"      : "②  자신의 경험",
            "option_3"      : "③  전문가의 의견",
            "option_4"      : "④  설문 조사 자료",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I'd like to talk about children's advertising. Did you know that you can't advertise sodas like coke or cider before 9 p.m. in Sweden? Advertising is also prohibited because soda is bad for children's health. According to experts, children are more affected by television commercials than adults. That's why we shouldn't broadcast advertisements that can harm children's health. There are many children who like soda in our country. I think we should ban these advertisements, at least when we mainly do children's programs.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  전문가의 의견",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [27~28] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "27. 여자의 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  취직을 하려면 개인 생활을 잘 관리해야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  인터넷에 글을 올릴 때는 조심할 필요가 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  인터넷을 통해 많은 정보를 얻을 수 있어서 좋다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  개인적인 글로 인해 채용에 불이익을 당해서는 안 된다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I heard that there was a person whose recruitment was canceled because of an article written on the Internet a while ago. But isn't your homepage a personal space? It doesn't make sense to cancel the recruitment with the writing there. Then who will post on the Internet? I understand that the company wants to hire good employees, but you shouldn't even investigate your personal life.\nMan : Of course, it would be ridiculous for a person whose recruitment was canceled. But it's up to the company to choose an employee. The company can also check what you wrote on the Internet to get information about applicants.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  개인적인 글로 인해 채용에 불이익을 당해서는 안 된다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [27~28] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "28. 남자의 생각이나 태도로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  조심스럽게 여자의 주장을 따르고 있다",
            "option_2"      : "②  여자의 의견을 무시하며 자신의 주장만 하고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  자신의 생각이 잘못되었음을 솔직히 인정하고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  여자의 말을 일부 인정하며 자신의 생각을 밝히고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I heard that there was a person whose recruitment was canceled because of an article written on the Internet a while ago. But isn't your homepage a personal space? It doesn't make sense to cancel the recruitment with the writing there. Then who will post on the Internet? I understand that the company wants to hire good employees, but you shouldn't even investigate your personal life.\nMan : Of course, it would be ridiculous for a person whose recruitment was canceled. But it's up to the company to choose an employee. The company can also check what you wrote on the Internet to get information about applicants.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  여자의 말을 일부 인정하며 자신의 생각을 밝히고 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [29~30] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "29. 이 뉴스의 제목으로 가장 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (4점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  가로등이 늘어나면서 어두웠던 골목길이 환해졌다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  사람들의 이동이 많아지면서 범죄율이 증가했다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  더 좋은 생활환경을 만들기 위해 좁은 길을 넓혔다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  벽에 그려진 그림으로 인해 사람들의 불안감이 커졌다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : It is said that Inju recently changed the environment to prevent crime. Reporter Park Eun-jung will tell you the detailed news.\nWoman : A narrow alley where people don't go, you can't help but feel anxious when you're alone. But when I drew a picture on the wall and increased the street lamp, the atmosphere became much brighter. As the atmosphere in the neighborhood changed, a lot of people started to go, and small shops opened. With changes in the environment, we expect that anxiety about the occurrence of crime will decrease and the actual crime rate will be lowered.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  더 좋은 생활환경을 만들기 위해 좁은 길을 넓혔다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [29~30] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "30. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (3점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  가로등이 늘어나면서 어두웠던 골목길이 환해졌다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  사람들의 이동이 많아지면서 범죄율이 증가했다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  더 좋은 생활환경을 만들기 위해 좁은 길을 넓혔다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  벽에 그려진 그림으로 인해 사람들의 불안감이 커졌다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : It is said that Inju recently changed the environment to prevent crime. Reporter Park Eun-jung will tell you the detailed news.\nWoman : A narrow alley where people don't go, you can't help but feel anxious when you're alone. But when I drew a picture on the wall and increased the street lamp, the atmosphere became much brighter. As the atmosphere in the neighborhood changed, a lot of people started to go, and small shops opened. With changes in the environment, we expect that anxiety about the occurrence of crime will decrease and the actual crime rate will be lowered.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  가로등이 늘어나면서 어두웠던 골목길이 환해졌다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        }
    ]
}
